Guide to the Elizabeth Grosz papers RL.11189
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Elizabeth Grosz papers
1973-2016
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture
RL.11189
36967
13.5 Linear Feet 9 boxes
Professional papers of Elizabeth Grosz, professor in the Gender, Sexuality, and Feminist Studies Department at Duke University. Materials include her scholarly work, teaching files, and her students' work.
Content Description
Professional papers of feminist philosopher, Elizabeth (Liz) Grosz: http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Elizabeth_Grosz. Materials encompass her scholarly work, including research files, manuscripts and typescripts of writings, publications, as well as student work, teaching files including syllabi, lecture notes, etc., and ephemera.
Biographical / Historical
Elizabeth Grosz is a philosopher and professor in the Women's Studies department at Duke University. Her research interests include the body, sexuality, space, time, and materiality. Previous institutions include University of Califoria, Santa Cruz, University of California, Davis, Johns Hopkins University, the University of Richmond, George Washington University, Harvard University, and the University of California, Irvine.
Her books include: Sexual Subversions: Three French Feminists (1989), Jacques Lacan: A Feminist Introduction (1990), Volatile Bodies: Toward a Corporeal Feminism (1994), Space, Time and Perversion: Essays on the Politics of Bodies (1995), Architecture from the Outside: Essays on Virtual and Real Space (2001), The Nick of Time: Politics, Evolution and the Untimely (2004), Time Travels: Feminism, Nature, Power (2005), Chaos, Territory, Art: Deleuze and the Framing of the Earth (2008), Becoming Undone. Darwinian Reflections on Life, Politics and Art (2011).
Feminism and higher education -- United States.; Education, Higher; Women -- Education; Women -- Education (Higher); Philosophy -- Study and teaching; Philosophy -- Study and teaching (Higher); Feminism; Feminism and higher education; Philosophy; Women's studies; Women's history; Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture
- Accession (2015-0029), 1978-2013
  - Volatile Bodies: Toward a Corporeal Feminism, undated (Box 1)
  - Psychoanalysis and the Social Construction of Subjectivity, 1980 (Box 1)
  - The Incorporeal: Ontology, Ethics, and the Limits of Materialism; Ethics as Ethology: An Ontologenesis of the world, 2nd draft, undated (Box 1)
  - The Presocratic Philosophers: A Critical History with a Selection of Texts, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Irigaray, the 4 Elements and the Divine, undated (Box 1)
  - Irigaray, 1989 (Box 1)
  - Semiotics II/III B, lecture notes, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Semiotics II/III B, notes, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Semiotics II/III B, contents, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Papunya Tula artists, 2009 (Box 1)
  - Introduction to Feminist Theory, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Revising the Book of Life, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Notes on Deleuse and other assorted articles, undated (Box 1)
  - Sexual difference as sexual selection, undated (Box 1)
  - Thought as Action: Feminist Theory Workshop, 2013 (Box 1)
  - Course outlines, 1987-1988 (Box 1)
  - Assorted Kristeva articles, 2006 (Box 1)
  - Notes on assorted articles, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Nietschze articles, undated (Box 1)
  - Wittgenstein option, 1973 (Box 1)
  - Feminism I, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Notions of Femininity II/III option, notes, 1980 (Box 2)
  - Notions of Femininity II/III option, 1980 (Box 2)
  - The Incorporeal, Ontology, Ethics, and the Embryogenesis of the World, undated (Box 2)
  - Deleuze, Seminar "A Thousand Tiny Sexes", 1988 (Box 2)
  - Women and Architecture paper, 1984 (Box 2)
  - Space, Time, and Bodies, undated (Box 2)
  - Theorizing Corporeality: Bodies, Sexuality, and the Feminist Academy: interview with Elizabeth Grosz, 1999 (Box 2)
  - The Thing, undated (Box 2)
  - Thinking of the New: Of Futures Yet Unthought, undated (Box 2)
  - A Thousand Tiny Sexes: Feminism and Rhizomatics, undated (Box 2)
  - "The Time of Architecture" and "Architectures of Excess", 2000 (Box 2)
  - Timpanaro's Limbo, 1977 (Box 2)
  - Volatile Bodies: Elizabeth Grosz in Volatile Conversation with Diane Chisholm, undated (Box 2)
  - The Time of Violence; Deconstruction and Value, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Women, Chora, Dwelling, undated (Box 2)
  - Women's Studies, Feminism, and the University, 1985 (Box 2)
  - Women and Writing: The Work of Juliia Kristeva in Perspective, 1982 (Box 2)
  - Bodies and Pleasures in Queer Theory, undated (Box 2)
  - Bodies-Cities, 1995 (Box 2)
  - The body of law: notes toward a theory of corporeal justice with Pheng Cheah, 1996 (Box 2)
  - Contemporary Theories of Power and Subjectivity, undated (Box 2)
  - Criticism, Feminism, and The Institution, 1990 (Box 2)
  - Deleuze's Bergson: Duration, the Virtual and the Politics of the Future, 2000 (Box 2)
  - Derrida, Irigaray and Deconstruction, undated (Box 2)
  - Desire, the body and recent French feminisms, undated (Box 2)
  - Desire, Bodies, and Representation, undated (Box 2)
  - Dora, Hysteria and Femininity, 1989 (Box 2)
  - Embodying Space: An Interview with Elizabeth Grosz, undated (Box 2)
  - Ethics, Eros, and Irigaray (Book Review), 1996 (Box 2)
  - Every picture tells a story: art and theory re-examined, 1987 (Box 2)
  - Experimental Desire: Rethinking Queer Subjectivity, 1994 (Box 2)
  - Feminism and Anti-Humanism, 1990 (Box 2)
  - Lived Spatiality: Spaces of Corporeal Desire, undated (Box 2)
  - Naked, 2001 (Box 2)
  - Love's Labours Lost: Marxism and Feminism with Mia Campion, 1991 (Box 2)
  - Naked, 2001 (Box 2)
  - Nietzsche and the stomach for knowledge, 1993 (Box 2)
  - Ontology and Equivication: Derrida's Politics of Sexual Difference, 1995 (Box 2)
  - Love Letters in the Sand, 1984 (Box 2)
  - Merleau-Ponty and Irigaray in the Flesh, 1993 (Box 2)
  - Note on the Thing, undated (Box 2)
  - On Speaking about Pornography, undated (Box 2)
  - Philosophy and Psychoanalysis and Feminism with Hazel Rowley, undated (Box 2)
  - The 'People of the Book' Representation and Alterity in Emmanuel Lewis, undated (Box 2)
  - The Problem of Theory, 2000 (Box 2)
  - Psychoanalysis and the Imaginary Body, 1995 (Box 2)
  - Reconfigured Bodies, 2000 (Box 2)
  - Reconfiguring Lesbian Desire, undated (Box 2)
  - Sexual Difference and the Problem of Essentialism, undated (Box 2)
  - Feminism and the Critique of Representation, 1988-1989 (Box 2)
  - Feminism and the Crisis of Reason, 1993 (Box 2)
  - Feminist Theory and the Challenge to Knowledge, 1987 (Box 2)
  - Feminist Theory and the Politics of Art, 1994 (Box 2)
  - Firmare con il sesso: il femminismo e la morte del l'autore, 1993 (Box 2)
  - Freaks, 1991 (Box 2)
  - French Feminisms and Representation, 1988 (Box 2)
  - The Future of Space: Toward an Architecture of Invention, 2001 (Box 2)
  - A Good Society: A Feminist Perspective, undated (Box 2)
  - The Hetero and the Homo: The Sexual Ethics of Luce Irigaray, 1994 (Box 2)
  - Histories of a Feminist Nature, undated (Box 2)
  - Identity and Difference: A Response, 1994 (Box 2)
  - Inscriptions and body-maps: representations and the corporeal, 1990 (Box 2)
  - Intolerable Ambiguity: Freaks as/at the Limit, undated (Box 2)
  - Irigaray's Notion of Sexual Morphology, 1993 (Box 2)
  - Irigaray and the Divine, 1994 (Box 2)
  - Judaism and Exile: The Ethics of Otherness, 1990 (Box 2)
  - The Labors of Love. Analyzing Perverse Desire..., 1994 (Box 2)
  - Lacan, the Symbolic, the Imaginary, and the Real, undated (Box 2)
  - Le corps et les connaissances. La feminisme et la crise de la raison, 1992 (Box 2)
  - Book agreements/correspondence, 1986-1998 (Box 2)
  - Employment correspondence, 1995-2001 (Box 3)
  - MIT press correspondence, 2000 (Box 3)
  - Penn State, 1995 (Box 3)
  - Rutgers course evaluations, 2002-2006 (Box 3)
  - Levings, undated (Box 3)
  - Notions of Femininity, 1980-2002 (Box 3)
  - Assorted articles, 1995-1997 (Box 3)
  - Derrida notes, undated (Box 3)
  - Assorted articles, 1990-1992 (Box 3)
  - Assorted articles, 1990-1999 (Box 3)
  - Assorted articles, 1990-1999 (Box 3)
  - Assorted articles, 1982-1996 (Box 3)
  - Semiotics II/III, 1988 (Box 3)
  - Post-Modernism, undated (Box 3)
  - Newspaper, magazine & journal reviews, 1994 (Box 3)
  - Photograph, undated (Box 3)
  - Assorted articles & correspondence, 1984-1995 (Box 3)
  - New Literary History - Semiotics, 1978 (Box 3)
  - Semiotics lectures, 1983 (Box 3)
  - Semiotics II/III notes, 1983 (Box 3)
  - Semiotics II/III lecture notes, 1981 (Box 3)
  - Intro to Semiotics II/III - notes, summaries, 1979 (Box 3)
  - Semiotics A notes, 1985 (Box 3)
  - Semiotics II/III lectures, 1985 (Box 3)
  - Semiotics II/III B, undated (Box 3)
  - Semiotics II/III B lectures, 1985 (Box 3)
  - Assorted Articles, 2005-2006 (Box 4)
  - University positions logistics, 2011 (Box 4)
  - Assorted articles, 2008 (Box 4)
  - Body papers, 1983-1987 (Box 4)
  - Graphics, undated (Box 4)
  - Cornell University School of Criticism & Theory Director, 2005 (Box 4)
  - Assorted articles, 2006-2007 (Box 4)
  - Reviews, 1994-2009 (Box 4)
  - Speaking engagements, 1995 (Box 4)
  - Freaks, 2006 (Box 4)
  - E Gross - reviews, 1979-1993 (Box 4)
  - Feminist Challenges reviews, 1987-1988 (Box 4)
  - Women and language, 1987 (Box 4)
  - Women, literature and language, 1986 (Box 4)
  - Feminism and textuality, 1989 (Box 4)
  - Assorted articles, 2002 (Box 4)
  - Papers on art, 1988 (Box 4)
  - Feminist Theory and the Representational Arts, 1986 (Box 4)
  - Art & Theory, undated (Box 4)
  - Lived Spatiality (The Spaces of Corporeal Desire), undated (Box 4)
  - Women in film and television, 1988 (Box 4)
  - The Body and Performance, 1987 (Box 4)
  - Naked, undated (Box 4)
  - Jacques Derrida and Deconstruction, undated (Box 4)
  - Feminism and Deconstruction: Irigaray and Derrida, 1988 (Box 4)
  - Derrida and Sexual Difference, undated (Box 4)
  - Psychoanalysis, Feminism, and Language; Workshop: Introduction, 1979-1982 (Box 4)
  - The Strange Detours of Sublimation: Psychoanalysis & Social Production, 1995 (Box 4)
  - Papers on psychoanalysis, 1983-2006 (Box 4)
  - Columbia University Newsline, 1995 (Box 4)
  - Lacan languages, undated (Box 4)
  - Johns Hopkins, 1994-1995 (Box 4)
  - Copies of articles, publications, 1981 (Box 4)
  - Feminist Theory, undated (Box 4)
  - Understanding Sex, 1990 (Box 4)
  - Refiguring Lesbian Desire, undated (Box 4)
  - Experimetal Desire: Bodies and Pleasure in Queer Theory, undated (Box 4)
  - Assorted articles, 1991 (Box 4)
  - Dialects, 1975 (Box 4)
  - General Systems Theory, 1975-1976 (Box 4)
  - Assorted articles, 1976 (Box 5)
  - Rutgers FOCUS, 2002 (Box 5)
  - Essentialism and Difference, undated (Box 5)
  - Contemporary Theories of Power, undated (Box 5)
  - Feminism and Deconstruction, 1985 (Box 5)
  - Irigaray & the Divine, 1990 (Box 5)
  - Derrida & Irigaray, undated (Box 5)
  - Papers on Irigaray, undated (Box 5)
  - Irigaray and the Sexual Economy; History Dept, 1987 (Box 5)
  - A Thousand Tiny Sexes, undated (Box 5)
  - Assorted articles, 1986-2007 (Box 5)
  - Book covers, undated (Box 5)
  - Interviews, undated (Box 5)
  - Appearances, 1985-2010 (Box 5)
  - Feminist Theory, 1978-2010 (Box 5)
  - Griffith talks, undated (Box 5)
  - Feminism and Social Theory, 1987 (Box 5)
  - Space, Time, and Bodies, 1990 (Box 5)
  - Oxford Latin Dictionary, 1982 (Box 5)
  - Assorted articles, 1992-1998 (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous articles, 1985 (Box 5)
  - Social/Political Theory; UCLA Political Science Seminar, 1990 (Box 5)
  - Feminism and Antihumanism, 1986-1987 (Box 5)
  - Feminism Representation and Politics/Inscriptions and Body-Maps, 1986-1989 (Box 5)
  - Feminist theory publications, 1985 (Box 5)
  - Thinking Otherwise: Methodologies of Feminist Theory book proposal/correspondence, 1986 (Box 5)
  - Feminist papers, 1985-1986 (Box 5)
  - Le corps et les connaissances - le feminisme et la crise de la Raison, 1992 (Box 5)
  - Science and Feminism, 1987 (Box 5)
  - Assorted articles, 2004 (Box 5)
  - Women and Science, undated (Box 5)
  - Virtual Bodies, 1991-1992 (Box 5)
  - Time Travels, 2005 (Box 5)
  - Freud Conference articles, 1976 (Box 5)
  - Assorted notes/articles, 1981-1994 (Box 5)
  - Landslides scripts and reviews, 1987 (Box 5)
  - Kristeva publications, 1985 (Box 5)
  - Feminism in Australia, 1989 (Box 5)
  - Lacan IV/V 1st semester, 1994 (Box 5)
  - Psychoanalysis & Feminism A, II/III, 1984 (Box 5)
  - Psychoanalysis & Feminism, 1978 (Box 5)
  - Irigaray, 1995 (Box 5)
  - Irigaray, 1995 (Box 6)
  - Kristeva, undated (Box 6)
  - Lacan IV, 1987 (Box 6)
  - Lacan IV, 1984 (Box 6)
  - Lacan IV/PG, 1989 (Box 6)
  - Freud IV option, 1987 (Box 6)
  - Freud option notes, 1977 (Box 6)
  - Introduction to Psychoanalysis II/III option, 1980 (Box 6)
  - Critique of Psychoanalysis IVth year option, 1980 (Box 6)
  - Psychoanalysis & Feminism II/III, 1982 (Box 6)
  - Psychoanalysis and Feminism B "The Unconscious", 1984 (Box 6)
  - NSWIT, Freud course, 1982 (Box 6)
  - Psychoanalysis and Feminism A copies, 1987 (Box 6)
  - Psychoanalysis and Feminism A lectures, 1987 (Box 6)
  - Foucault IV, lectures, 1985 (Box 6)
  - Notes on the Body, undated (Box 6)
  - Feminism and the Crisis of Reason, 1991 (Box 6)
  - Assorted articles, undated (Box 6)
  - Papers on Foucault, 2000 (Box 6)
  - Papers on the body, 1986 (Box 6)
  - Semiotics notes, 1983 (Box 6)
  - Foucault, Body/Power, undated (Box 6)
  - Philosophy of the Body book, undated (Box 6)
  - Body book: bibliography, 1989 (Box 6)
  - University of California - Irvine, 1994-1995 (Box 6)
  - General Philosophy, Sydney University, 2006 (Box 6)
  - Power & Desire: Foucault and Deleuze IV/V, 1993 (Box 6)
  - Lacan summaries, undated (Box 7)
  - Jacques Lacan television, 1987 (Box 7)
  - Jacques Lacan articles, undated (Box 7)
  - Lacan IV Lecture notes, 1982 (Box 7)
  - Lacan IV, 1982 (Box 7)
  - Linguistics notes, 1976 (Box 7)
  - The Floating Eye, 1990 (Box 7)
  - Wilden System & Structure, undated (Box 7)
  - Psychoanalysis & Feminism II/III, 1978-1982 (Box 7)
  - Notions of Femininity, lecture notes, 1982 (Box 7)
  - Feminism I, lecture notes, 1980 (Box 7)
  - Foucault IV, lecture notes, 1981 (Box 7)
  - The Philosophy of Desire IV, 1979 (Box 7)
  - Feminism I lecture notes, 1982 (Box 7)
  - Feminism I, 1979-1982 (Box 7)
  - Psychoanalysis & Feminism B II/III, 1987 (Box 7)
  - Lacan, 1984-1987 (Box 7)
  - Philosophy of the Body II/IV lectures, 1986 (Box 7)
  - Philosophy of the Body II/III lectures, 1986 (Box 7)
  - Sexual Difference II/III core course, 1991 (Box 7)
  - Introduction to Feminist Theory lectures, 1987 (Box 7)
  - Introduction to Feminist Theory: reading materials, 1987 (Box 7)
  - Notions of Femininity, 1984-1991 (Box 7)
  - Feminism I lectures, 1986 (Box 7)
- Accession (2017-0211), 1976-2016; 2
  - "Politics of Imperceptibility", 2002 (Box 8)
    Scope and Contents
    Article in Philosophy and Social Criticism
  - "Lesbian Fetishism", 2001 (Box 8)
    Article in Journal for Politics, Gender, and Culture (Russian)
  - "Reconfigured Bodies", 2000 (Box 8)
    Article in Embodying Gender (Spanish)
  - "Judaism and Exile: The Ethics of Otherness", 1999 (Box 8)
    Article in New Formations
  - "Deleuze, Bergson and the Concept of Life", 2007 (Box 8)
    Article in International Journal of Philosophy
  - Correspondence from Luce Irigary, 2005-2011 (Box 8)
  - "Little Hans: The Production of Oedipus, 1978 (Box 8)
    Article in Language Sexuality and Subversion
  - Working Papers in Sex, Science, and Culture journals, 1976-1977 (Box 8)
  - Intervention: Revolutionary Marxist Journal, 1977 (Box 8)
  - The Incorporeal: Ontology, Ethics and the Limits of Materialism, 2016; 4 folders (Box 8)
    Manuscript of book
  - Translations of Luce Irigary's articles and interviews, 1975-1981 (Box 8)
  - Interview with Gayatri Spivak, 1984 (Box 8)
  - Print entitled "Dryads", 1978 (Box 8)
    Signed: for Liz, with love M.
  - Upside Down World Map (Australia), 2001 (Box 8)
    includes map, reciept, and Columbia University sticker
  - Architecture New York journal issues, 1993-1997 (Oversize-box 9)
    Issues 0-20